The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: So we're going to do rolling caches then,
教授：那么我们将要滚动缓存，
we're going to go a little bit over amortized analysis
我们将对摊销分析进行一些讨论
and if we have a lot of time left,
如果我们还有很多时间，
we're going to talk about good and bad hash functions.
我们将讨论好的和坏的哈希函数。
So can someone remind me what's the point of rolling hashes?
那么有人可以提醒我滚动哈希的意义是什么？
What's the problem?
有什么问题？
What are we trying to solve in lectures?
我们要在讲座中解决什么？
Be brave.
勇敢起来。
AUDIENCE: Gets faster, I think, because like--
听众：我觉得更快，因为
PROFESSOR: So what are we trying to solve?
教授：那我们要解决什么？
You don't need to go ahead, tell me
你不用说了
what's the big problem that we're trying to solve.
我们要解决的最大问题是什么？
AUDIENCE: I don't remember/
听众：我不记得/
PROFESSOR: OK, so let's go over that.
教授：好的，让我们解决一下。
So we have a big document, AKA a long string,
所以我们有一个大文件，又是一个长字符串，
and we're trying to find a smaller string inside it.
并且我们正在尝试在其中找到一个较小的字符串。
And we're trying to do that efficiently.
我们正在努力有效地做到这一点。
So say the big document is-- you might have seen this before.
所以说大文件是-您以前可能已经看过。
And we're trying to look for the here.
我们正在尝试在这里寻找。
How do I do that with rolling hashes?
如何使用滚动哈希做到这一点？
So the slow, nice solution is I get this the
所以，缓慢，不错的解决方案是
and then I overlap with the beginning of the document,
然后我与文档的开头重叠，
I do a string comparison.
我进行字符串比较。
If it matches, I say that it's a match.
如果匹配，我说这是匹配。
It's not, I overlap it here.
不是，我在这里重叠。
String match, I overlap it here.
字符串匹配，我在这里重叠。
String match, so on and so forth.
字符串匹配，依此类推。
The problem is this does a lot of string matching operations,
问题是这会执行很多字符串匹配操作，
and the string matching operation is how expensive?
和字符串匹配操作多少钱？
What's the running time?
几点钟了？
AUDIENCE: Order n.
观众：订单n。
PROFESSOR: Order n, where n is the size of the string.
教授：n阶，其中n是字符串的大小。
So if we have a string, say this is the key
所以如果我们有一个字符串，那就说这是关键
that we're looking for and n is the document size then
我们正在寻找的n是文档大小，然后
this is going to be order n times k.
这将是k的n阶。
We want to get to something better.
我们想要变得更好。
So how do I do this with rolling hashes?
那么我该如何使用滚动哈希值呢？
AUDIENCE: We take the strings up,
观众：我们把线拉起来，
and you come up with a hash code for it.
然后您想出了一个哈希码。
PROFESSOR: OK so we're going to hash this.
教授：好的，我们将对此进行哈希处理。
And let's say this is the key hash.
假设这是关键哈希。
OK, very good.
好的，棒极了。
AUDIENCE: And then once you know that, then you'll
听众：然后，一旦你知道了，你就会
need to compute the next letter hash,
需要计算下一个字母哈希，
or just add it on to that pairing.
或只是将其添加到该配对中。
PROFESSOR: OK, so next letter for--
教授：好的，下一封信是-
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
So you compute the hash of the entire string, n, capital n--
因此，您需要计算整个字符串的散列n，大写n--
PROFESSOR: Let's not do that.
教授：我们不要那样做。
Let's compute the hash of the first key characters
让我们计算第一个关键字符的哈希值
in the string.
在字符串中。
AUDIENCE: Are we separating them by space [? inside? ?]
听众：我们是否将它们按空格分开？内？ ？]
PROFESSOR: Yeah, so this is going to be a character.
教授：是的，所以这将是一个角色。
AUDIENCE: The space will?
听众：空间会吗？
PROFESSOR: Sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: The space will be a character?
听众：空格将是一个字符？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
So let's take the first three characters
因此，让我们取前三个字符
and compute the hash of that.
并计算其哈希值。
And let's call this the our sliding window.
我们称其为滑动窗口。
So we're going to say that window has the
因此，我们要说该窗口具有
and then we're going to compute the hash of the characters
然后我们将计算字符的哈希值
in the window, and we're going to see
在窗口中，我们将看到
that this matches the hash of the key.
匹配密钥的哈希值。
And then we'll figure out what to do.
然后我们会弄清楚该怎么做。
That aside, we're going to slide the window
顺便说一句，我们将滑动窗口
to the right by one character so take out
向右移一个字符，所以取出
key and put in the space.
钥匙，放在空间中。
And now the window has HE space, we're
现在窗户上有他的空间，我们
going to compute the hash of the window,
要计算窗口的哈希值，
see that it's not the same as this hash of the key.
看到它与密钥的哈希值不同。
What do we know in this case?
在这种情况下我们知道些什么？
Different hashes means--
不同的哈希手段-
AUDIENCE: Not the same string.
听众：字符串不同。
PROFESSOR: For sure not the same string.
教授：请确保不是相同的字符串。
So this is not the.
所以这不是。
OK, now suppose I'm sliding my window
好吧，现在假设我正在滑动窗口
so after this I will slide my window again,
因此之后，我将再次滑动窗口，
and I would have e space f.
我会有e空间f。
Right, so on and so forth.
是的，依此类推。
Suppose I'm happy sliding my window and then I get here
假设我很高兴滑动窗户然后到达这里
and I have my window be IN space, and the hash the window
我的窗口在空间中，然后将窗口散列
happens to match the hash of the key.
碰巧匹配密钥的哈希值。
So we're in the same situation as here.
因此，我们处于与这里相同的情况。
Now what?
怎么办？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Very good.
教授：非常好。
We have to check if the string inside the window
我们必须检查窗口中的字符串是否
is the same as the string inside the key.
与键中的字符串相同。
And if it is, we found a match.
如果是这样，我们找到了一个匹配项。
If it isn't, we keep working.
如果不是，我们会继续努力。
All right?
好吧？
And we have to do the same thing here.
我们必须在这里做同样的事情。
So this is our string matching algorithm.
这就是我们的字符串匹配算法。
AUDIENCE: Can we somehow make sure that we make a hash
观众：我们能以某种方式确保我们进行哈希运算吗
function such that it will never [INAUDIBLE]--
功能使其永远不会[听不清]-
PROFESSOR: Excellent question.
教授：很好的问题。
Thank you, I like that.
谢谢，我喜欢
Can we make a hash function so that we
我们可以做一个哈希函数，这样我们
don't have any false positives, right?
没有误报吧？
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
How do hash functions work?
哈希函数如何工作？
What's the argument to a hash function
哈希函数的参数是什么
and what's the return value?
的返回值是多少？
AUDIENCE: The argument is something
听众：论点是什么
that you want to hash.
您想散列。
PROFESSOR: So in this case we're working with three character
教授：所以在这种情况下，我们使用三个字符
strings.
字符串。
But let's say we're looking for a one megabyte
但是，假设我们正在寻找一个1 MB的字节
string inside the one gigabyte string.
一个千兆字节字符串中的字符串。
Say we're a music company and we're
说我们是一家音乐公司，
looking for our mp3 file inside the big files
在大文件中寻找我们的mp3文件
off a pirate server or something.
关闭海盗服务器之类的东西。
So this is 1 million character strings,
这是一百万个字符串，
because that's the window size.
因为那是窗口大小。
And it's going to return what?
它会返回什么？
What do hash functions return for them to be useful?
哈希函数返回什么对它们有用？
Integers.
整数。
Nice small integers, right?
漂亮的小整数，对不对？
Ideally, the integer would fit in a word size, where
理想情况下，整数将适合字长，其中
the word is the register size on our computer.
这个词是我们计算机上的寄存器大小。
What are popular word sizes?
什么是流行字号？
Does anyone know?
有人知道吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
AUDIENCE: Excellent.
听众：很好。
32-bits, 64-bits integers.
32位，64位整数。
OK, so what's the universe size for this function?
好，那么此函数的Universe大小是多少？
How many one million character strings are there?
有几百万个字符串？
AUDIENCE: How many characters are there?
听众：有几个字符？
PROFESSOR: Excellent.
教授：非常好。
Let's say we're old school and we're doing [? SG ?].
假设我们是老学校，我们正在[ SG？]。
We don't care about the rest of the world.
我们不在乎世界其他地方。
AUDIENCE: 256 characters?
听众：256个字符？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: To the one millionth power.
听众：达到百万分之一的权力。
PROFESSOR: Cool.
教授：太好了。
Let's say we're working on an old school computer,
假设我们正在使用一台老式计算机，
since we're old school and we have a 32-bit word size.
由于我们是守旧派，而且字长为32位。
How many possible values for the hash function?
哈希函数有多少个可能的值？
AUDIENCE: 2 to the 32.
听众：2至32。
PROFESSOR: The [? other ?] is bigger.
教授：[？其他？]更大。
You're messing with me, right?
你惹我了吧
OK so this is 2 to the 8th.
好的，所以这是2到8。
AUDIENCE: 2 to the 8 million, right?
听众：800万中的2对吧？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So this is a lot bigger than this.
因此，这比这要大得多。
So if we want to make a hash function that gives us
因此，如果我们要创建一个散列函数
no false positives, then we'd have
没有误报，那么我们将
to be able to-- if we have the universe of possible inputs
能够-如果我们拥有大量可能的投入
and the universe of possible outputs,
以及所有可能的输出，
draw a line from every input to a different output.
从每个输入到另一个输出画一条线。
But if we have-- 2 to the 32 by the way is about four billion.
但是如果有的话，顺便说一句，32到2大约是40亿。
If we have four billion outputs and a lot of inputs
如果我们有40亿个产出和大量投入
as we draw our lines, we're eventually
当我们划清界限时，我们最终
going to run out of outputs and we're
将要用完输出，我们
going to have to use the same output again and again.
将不得不一次又一次使用相同的输出。
So for a hash function, pretty much always
因此，对于哈希函数，几乎总是
the universe size is bigger than the output size.
Universe大小大于输出大小。
So hash functions will always have collisions.
因此，哈希函数将始终存在冲突。
So a collision for a hash function
所以哈希函数的冲突
is two inputs, x1, x2, so that's x1 is not x2, but h of x1
是两个输入x1，x2，所以x1不是x2，而是x1的h
equals h of x2.
等于x2的h。
So this will always happen.
因此，这将永远发生。
There's no way around it.
没有办法解决。
What we're hoping for is that the collisions
我们希望的是碰撞
aren't something dumb.
没什么傻
So we're hoping that the hash function acts
所以我们希望哈希函数起作用
in a reasonably randomly and we talked about ideal hash
在合理的随机范围内，我们讨论了理想的哈希
functions that would pretty much look like they would get
看起来很像的功能
a random output for every input.
每个输入的随机输出。
And we're not going to worry too much about that.
我们不会为此担心太多。
What matters is that as long as the hash function is reasonably
重要的是，只要哈希函数合理
good, we're not going to have too many false positives.
好，我们不会有太多误报。
So say the output set is O, so O is 2 to the 32.
假设输出集是O，所以O是32的2。
Then we're hoping to have false positives about one
然后，我们希望对某人产生误报
every O times.
每O次。
So 1 out of 2 to the 32 false positives.
因此，在32个误报中有2分之1。
So what's the running time for when you slide the window
那么滑动窗口的时间是多少
and we're doing this logic here.
我们在这里做这个逻辑。
What's the running time if the hashes aren't the same?
如果哈希值不同，那么运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: What's the running time of the hash function--
听众：哈希函数的运行时间是多少？
PROFESSOR: Of the whole matching algorithm.
教授：整个匹配算法中。
AUDIENCE: No, no no, of the hash function itself.
听众：不，不，不，哈希函数本身。
Can we make any assumptions about that?
我们可以对此做出任何假设吗？
Very good.
很好。
What's the running time of the hash function?
哈希函数的运行时间是多少？
So we're going to have to implement--
所以我们将不得不实施
if we implement the hash function naively,
如果我们天真的实现哈希函数，
then the running time for hashing a key character string
然后散列关键字符串的运行时间
is order key.
是订单密钥。
But we're going to come up with magic way of doing it
但是，我们将提出一种神奇的方法
in order one time.
为了一次。
So assume hashing is order 1.
因此，假设哈希为阶数1。
What's the running time for everything else?
其他一切的运行时间是多少？
So if the hashes don't match, we know it's not a candidate.
因此，如果哈希值不匹配，我们就知道它不是候选对象。
So we're going to keep going.
因此，我们将继续前进。
So this is order 1.
所以这是命令1。
What if the hashes do match?
如果哈希匹配，该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] characters.
观众：[音频不清晰]个字符。
PROFESSOR: Order--
教授：命令-
AUDIENCE: I mean, but it depends on how many ones match,
听众：我的意思是，但这取决于匹配的数量，
but it will be--
但它将是-
PROFESSOR: So for one match, what's
教授：那么一场比赛是什么
the running time for one match?
一场比赛的时间？
AUDIENCE: Order k--
听众：订单k--
PROFESSOR: Order k.
教授：命令k。
Excellent.
优秀的。
So the total running time is the number of matches times
因此，总运行时间就是匹配次数
order k plus the number of non matches times order 1.
顺序k加上不匹配数乘以顺序1。
So as long as the number of false positives
所以只要误报数量
here is really tiny, the math is going
这真的很小，数学将进行
to come out to be roughly order 1 per character.
大约是每个字符1。
AUDIENCE: So the whole thing is order in.
听众：所以整个过程都在整理之中。
PROFESSOR: Everything should be order n, yeah,
教授：一切都应为n，是的，
that's what we're hoping for.
这就是我们所希望的。
OK so let's talk about the magic because you asked me
好吧，让我们谈谈魔术，因为你问我
what's the running time for the hash function
哈希函数的运行时间是多少
and this is the interesting part.
这是有趣的部分。
How do I get to compute these hashes
我如何计算这些哈希
and order 1 instead of order k?
和顺序1而不是顺序k？
We have this data structure called rolling hash.
我们有一个称为滚动哈希的数据结构。
So rolling hash-- does anyone remember
所以滚动哈希-有谁记得
from lecture what it is?
从讲座是什么？
AUDIENCE: Isn't that what we're doing right now?
听众：这不是我们现在正在做的吗？
PROFESSOR: So this is a sliding window.
教授：这是一个滑动窗口。
And the data structure will compute fast hashes
数据结构将计算快速哈希
for the strings inside the sliding window.
用于滑动窗口内的字符串。
So how does it work?
那么它是怎样工作的？
I mean not how does it work functionally, what
我的意思是说它不是如何工作的，
are the operations for a rolling hash, let's try that.
是滚动哈希的操作，请尝试一下。
AUDIENCE: Oh [INAUDIBLE].
听众：哦[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, so we have two updates.
教授：好的，我们进行了两次更新。
One of them is pop.
其中之一是流行音乐。
For some reason, our notes call it skip,
由于某些原因，我们的注释将其称为“跳过”，
but I like pop better, so I'm going
但我更喜欢流行音乐，所以我要
to write skip and think pop.
写跳过和思考流行。
And the other one is?
而另一个是？
AUDIENCE: Always [INAUDIBLE].
听众：始终[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: A pen with a new character, OK?
教授：一支新字符的笔，好吗？
Cool.
凉。
So these are the updates.
这些是更新。
Now what's the point of those updates?
现在这些更新的意义是什么？
What's the query for a rolling hash?
对滚动哈希的查询是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
You just grab the next character,
你只要抓住下一个角色，
append that, and then skip [INAUDIBLE].
追加，然后跳过[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, so this is how I update the rolling hash
教授：好的，这就是我更新滚动哈希的方法
to contain to reflect the contents of my sliding window.
包含以反映我滑动窗口的内容。
And what I do after that?
那之后我该怎么办？
What's the reason for that?
是什么原因呢？
AUDIENCE: You skip your [INAUDIBLE].
听众：您跳过了[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So don't think too hard, it's
教授：所以不要太刻苦，这是
a really easy question.
一个非常简单的问题。
I moved a sliding window here.
我在这里移动了一个滑动窗口。
What do I want to get?
我想得到什么？
AUDIENCE: You want to get the hash of those characters.
听众：您想获得这些字符的哈希值。
PROFESSOR: The hash of those characters, very good.
教授：这些字符的哈希值非常好。
So this is the query.
这就是查询。
So a rolling hash has a sequence of characters in it, right?
因此滚动哈希表中包含一系列字符，对吗？
Say t, h, e.
说t，h，e。
And it allows us to append the character and pop a character.
它允许我们追加角色并弹出角色。
Append a character, pop a character.
追加一个字符，弹出一个字符。
And then it promises that it's going
然后承诺会
to compute the hash of whatever's inside
计算里面的哈希值
the rolling hash really fast.
滚动哈希非常快。
Append goes here, skip goes here.
追加到这里，跳过到这里。
How fast do these operations need
这些操作需要多快
to be for my algorithm to work correctly?
为我的算法正常工作？
AUDIENCE: Order 1.
受众：订单1。
PROFESSOR: I promised you that computing
教授：我答应过你
hash there is order 1, right?
哈希有顺序1，对吗？
So I have to-- OK.
所以我必须-好。
Let's see how we're going to make this happen.
让我们看看如何实现这一目标。
So these are letters.
这些是字母。
These make sense when we're trying
这些在我们尝试时很有意义
to understand string matching.
了解字符串匹配。
But now we're going to switch the numbers, because after all,
但是现在我们要切换数字，因为毕竟
strings are sequences of characters,
字符串是字符序列，
and characters are numbers.
和字符是数字。
And because I know how to do math on numbers,
而且因为我知道如何对数字进行数学运算，
I don't know how to do math on characters.
我不知道如何对角色进行数学运算。
So let's use this list.
因此，让我们使用此列表。
Let's say that instead of having numbers in base 256
假设不是以256为底的数字
which is [INAUDIBLE], we're going
这是[听不清]，我们要
to have numbers in base 100, because it's really easy to do
以100为基数，因为这很容易做到
operations in base 100 on paper.
在纸上以100为基础的操作
So 3, 14, 15, 92, 55, 35, 89, 79, 31.
所以3、14、15、92、55、35、89、79、31。
So these are all base 100 numbers.
这些都是以100为基数的数字。
And say my rolling window is size 5.
并说我的滚动窗口是5号。
One, two, three, four, five.
一二三四五。
So I want to come up with a way so that I have the hash of this
所以我想出一种方法让我知道这个
and then when I slide my window, I will get the hash of this.
然后，当我滑动窗口时，我会得到它的哈希值。
What hashing method do we use for rolling hashes?
我们使用哪种哈希方法来滚动哈希？
Does anyone remember?
有人记得吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Mod, you said-- I heard mod something.
教授：Mod，你说过-我听过Mod的话。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, that's what I said.
听众：是的，我就是这么说的。
PROFESSOR: OK, so?
教授：好吧？
So?
所以？
So the hash is?
哈希是吗？
The hash of a key is?
密钥的哈希是？
AUDIENCE: It's k mod m or m k.
听众：是k mod m或m k。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
I'm going to say k mod something,
我要说的是k mod
and I'm going to say that something
我要说的是
has to be a prime number and we'll see why in a bit.
必须是素数，稍后我们将说明原因。
Let's say our prime number is 23.
假设我们的素数是23。
So let's compute the value of the hash for the sliding window
因此，让我们计算滑动窗口的哈希值
of the first sliding window and then we'll
的第一个滑动窗口，然后我们将
compute the hash for the second sliding window.
计算第二个滑动窗口的哈希值。
Oh, there is some at the computer, sweet.
哦，计算机上有些东西，很贴心。
314159265 modulo 23 is how much?
314159265模23是多少？
OK, while you're doing that, can someone
好吧，当你这样做的时候，有人可以
tell me what computation will he need
告诉我他需要什么计算
to do for the second sliding window?
做第二个滑动窗口？
AUDIENCE: 1519265359.
观众：1519265359。
PROFESSOR: 159265359.
教授：159265359。
AUDIENCE: That's a third sign.
听众：这是第三个信号。
AUDIENCE: There's a 1-4 before that.
听众：在那之前是1-4。
AUDIENCE: The first one is 11.
听众：第一个是11。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
And what's the second one?
第二个是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] adding--
观众：[听不清]添加-
PROFESSOR: 1415926335 modulo 23.
教授：1415926335模23
AUDIENCE: 5.
听众：5。
PROFESSOR: I heard a 5 and a 7.
教授：我听到了5和7。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: Hold on, hold on.
听众：等一下，等一下。
PROFESSOR: I'll take the average of those two
教授：我取这两个的平均值
and we can move on, right?
我们可以继续吧？
AUDIENCE: Three five, and arguably 6.
听众：三五，可以说是六。
PROFESSOR: All right, so let's implement
教授：好的，让我们实施
an operation called slide.
称为幻灯片的操作。
And slide will take the new number that I'm sliding in.
幻灯片将采用我要输入的新数字。
And the old number that I'm sliding out,
还有我要滑出的旧号码，
making my life really easy.
使我的生活变得非常轻松。
So in this case, the numbers would be--
因此，在这种情况下，数字将是-
AUDIENCE: The new one is 35.
听众：新的是35。
PROFESSOR: And the old one?
教授：那是旧的？
AUDIENCE: 3.
听众：3。
PROFESSOR: Excellent.
教授：非常好。
And I want to have an internal state called hash that has 11
我想要一个内部状态称为hash的哈希值为11
and I want to get 6 after I'm done running slide.
我想在完成幻灯片播放后获得6分。
This is still too hard for me, so before we figure out hash,
这对我来说仍然太难了，所以在弄清楚哈希之前，
let's say that we have an internal state called n.
假设我们有一个称为n的内部状态。
And n is this big number here.
n在这里是这个大数字。
So I want to get from this big number to this big number.
所以我想从这个大数字变成这个大数字。
What am I going to do?
我要怎么办
AUDIENCE: Mod 3,000 [INAUDIBLE].
观众：模组3,000 [听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, so you want to take the big number 159265
教授：好的，所以您想取大数159265
and mod it.
并修改它。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: So if I mod it to by a big number,
教授：所以，如果我将其大量修改，
that's going to be too slow.
那太慢了。
So I can't mod it.
所以我不能修改它。
AUDIENCE: Can't you just divide it?
听众：你不能分开吗？
PROFESSOR: Division is also slow,
教授：划分也很慢，
I don't like the division.
我不喜欢这个部门。
I like subtraction, someone said subtraction.
我喜欢减法，有人说减法。
So what I want to do is I want to get from here to a number
所以我想做的就是从这里得到一个数字
that-- to this number, right?
-这个数字，对不对？
So I want to get rid of the 3 and I
所以我想摆脱3，我
want to add 35 at the end.
想要在末尾添加35。
To get rid of the 3, what do I subtract?
要摆脱3，我要减去什么？
AUDIENCE: 3 with a bunch of 0s.
听众：3，一堆0。
PROFESSOR: 3 with a bunch of 0s.
教授：3，一堆0。
Excellent.
优秀的。
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
1、2、3、4、5、6、7、8
How many of them are there?
有多少个？
AUDIENCE: 8.
听众：8。
PROFESSOR: OK, how many digits conveys 100?
教授：好的，多少位数字表示100？
AUDIENCE: Oh, 2 right?
听众：哦，对2吗？
AUDIENCE: 4.
听众：4。
AUDIENCE: Oh, oh.
听众：哦，哦。
PROFESSOR: 4.
教授：4。
So base 100, so two numbers--
所以以100为底，所以有两个数字-
AUDIENCE: One base 100 number is two digits.
听众：一个以100为基数的数字是两位数。
Yep.
是的
PROFESSOR: So 8.
教授：所以8。
yeah, OK, 4.
是的，好的4。
Cool.
凉。
So let's try to write this in a more abstract way.
因此，让我们尝试以一种更抽象的方式编写此代码。
So n is the old n minus old, right,
所以n是旧的n减去旧的，对，
so that 3 is old times what do I have to multiply it by
所以3是旧时代，我必须乘以
to get all those zeros?
得到所有那些零？
k minus 1?
k减1？
[INAUDIBLE] to that base whatever.
[听不清]以此为基础。
PROFESSOR: OK, so-- base to the size to something.
教授：好的，所以-根据大小来决定。
K minus 1.
K减1。
So K is 5 in this case, right?
所以在这种情况下K是5，对吗？
My window is 5.
我的窗口是5。
And I see a 4 there, so I'm going to add the minus 1
我在那里看到一个4，所以我要加上负1
just because that's what I need to do.
只是因为那是我需要做的。
OK, so then I get 14159265.
好，那么我得到14159265。
What do I do to tack on a 35 at the end?
我该怎么做才能在35时结束？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] 35.
观众：[听不清] 35。
PROFESSOR: OK, times the base, so that's
教授：好的，乘以基数，所以
going to give me the zeroes.
要给我零。
And then this is a minus here.
然后这是一个负号。
And then I'm going to add 35.
然后我要添加35。
Right?
对？
1415926535.
1415926535。
Look, it's right.
看，是对的。
So what do I write here?
那我在这里写什么呢？
AUDIENCE: The base first.
听众：基础第一。
PROFESSOR: Good point.
教授：很好。
OK.
好。
Let me play with this a little bit before we go further.
在继续之前，让我玩一点。
I'm going to distribute the base here.
我要在这里分配基地。
So this is n times base minus old times
所以这是n乘以基础减去以前
base to the k plus mu.
以k加亩为基数。
And let's rename base to size to be the size of the window,
让我们将base重命名为大小，使其等于窗口的大小，
I don't like k.
我不喜欢k。
And I'm renaming it because later on we're
我正在重命名，因为稍后
going to break our slide into appends and skip
要将幻灯片分成附录并跳过
and the size won't be constant anymore.
并且大小将不再恒定。
OK so does this make sense?
好的，这有意义吗？
It's all math.
这都是数学。
So this math here becomes abstract math here.
因此，这里的数学变成了抽象数学。
But nothing else changes.
但是没有其他改变。
OK, so now I want to get hash-- I
好吧，现在我想获取哈希值-我
want to get hash out of n, how do I do that?
想要从n中获取哈希，我该怎么做？
AUDIENCE: Mod 23.
听众：Mod 23。
PROFESSOR: Mod 23, very good.
教授：Mod 23，非常好。
So in a general way, I would say mod p.
因此，总的来说，我会说mod p。
OK so hash is n times base minus old times
OK，所以哈希是n乘以n减去以前的乘积
base to the size plus new mod p.
根据大小加上新的mod p。
Now let's distribute this.
现在让我们分发它。
I know I can distribute modulo across addition
我知道我可以跨加法分配模
and subtraction, so I have n mod p times base minus old times
加减，所以我有n mod p乘以基础减去以前的乘积
base to the size mod p plus new.
以mod p加上新大小为基础。
And everything still has to be a mod p.
一切仍然必须是mod p。
So can someone tell me where did I add the mod p?
那么有人可以告诉我我在哪里添加了mod p吗？
Why did I put it here and here?
我为什么把它放在这里和这里？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] the original?
听众：[听不清]原件？
PROFESSOR: OK, nmodp is hash, let's do that.
教授：好的，nmodp是哈希，让我们开始吧。
So what's true about both n and base to the size?
那么，n和以大小为基的情况如何呢？
AUDIENCE: Constant.
听众：不变。
PROFESSOR: Constant?
教授：恒定吗？
AUDIENCE: Like can you please repeat it?
听众：就像你能重复一遍吗？
AUDIENCE: You could [INAUDIBLE] base to the size but you
听众：您可以[听不清]根据大小，但是
can't [INAUDIBLE] hash, I mean [INAUDIBLE]--
不能[听不清]哈希，我的意思是[听不清]-
PROFESSOR: Hm.
教授：嗯。
OK, so keep this in mind that we can compute this,
好的，请记住这一点，我们可以进行计算，
because we're going to want to do that later.
因为我们要稍后再做。
But what I had in mind is the opposite of constant,
但是我想到的是常数的反面，
because n is huge.
因为n很大
Right?
对？
And base to the size is also huge, right?
而且底座的尺寸也很大吧？
N is this number.
N是这个数字。
Base to the size is this number here.
基于大小的是此数字。
1 followed by this many zeros, so these numbers are big.
1后面跟着这么多的零，所以这些数字很大。
All the other numbers are small.
所有其他数字都很小。
Base is small, old is small, new is small, p is small.
基数小，旧的小，新的小，p小。
PROFESSOR: So I want to get rid of the big numbers,
教授：所以我想摆脱大数字，
because math with big numbers is slow.
因为大数的数学运算很慢。
So unless I get rid of the big numbers,
因此，除非我摆脱了大数字，
I'm not going to get to order 1 operation.
我不会去订购1号手术。
So we already got rid of this one because it's hash
所以我们已经摆脱了这个，因为它是哈希
and how do I get rid of this one?
以及我该如何摆脱呢？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
AUDIENCE: There's some 6042 algorithm
听众：有一些6042算法
that does that quickly.
很快就能做到。
AUDIENCE: Well, we definitely just went over this in class
听众：好吧，我们绝对是在上课时
today.
今天。
AUDIENCE: Which is why you needed the prime number, right?
听众：这就是为什么您需要素数，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Not quite.
教授：不完全是。
There is an algorithm that does it quickly.
有一种算法可以快速完成。
That algorithm is called repeated squaring
该算法称为重复平方
and the quickest-- wait, I'm not done, I promise I'm not done.
最快-等待，我还没有完成，我保证我还没有完成。
So the quickest that this guy can
所以这家伙可以最快
run if you do everything right is order of [? log ?] size.
如果一切正确，请运行[？ log？]大小。
If the window size is 1 megabyte,
如果视窗大小为1 MB，
10 megabytes, if the window size keeps growing,
10 MB，如果窗口大小持续增长，
if the window size is part of the input size,
如果窗口大小是输入大小的一部分，
is this constant?
这个常数吗？
Nope.
不。
So I can't do that.
所以我不能那样做。
Someone else gave me the right answer before.
之前有人给我正确的答案。
What did you say before?
你刚才说什么
AUDIENCE: Pre-compute it?
听众：预先计算吗？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
It's a constant, so why don't we pre-compute it?
这是一个常数，所以为什么不预先计算呢？
Take it out of here, compute it once,
从这里取出，计算一次，
and after that, we can use it all the time.
之后，我们可以一直使用它。
And unless someone has a better name for it,
除非有人对此有更好的名字，
I'm going to call this magic.
我将称之为魔术。
The name has to be short, by the way,
顺便说一下，这个名字必须简短
because I'll be writing this a few times.
因为我会写几次。
OK, so now we have hash equals hash times base
好，现在我们的哈希等于哈希乘以基数
minus old times magic plus new modulo p.
减去旧时代的魔法加上新的模数p。
Doesn't look too bad, right?
看起来还不错吧？
Pretty constant time.
相当恒定的时间。
Now let's write the pseudo code for the rolling hash,
现在让我们为滚动哈希编写伪代码，
and let's break this out into an append
让我们将其分解为一个附录
and a skip at the same time.
并同时跳过
AUDIENCE: What if hash is bigger than your word size?
听众：如果哈希大于您的单词大小怎么办？
PROFESSOR: So hash is always going to be something modulo p.
教授：因此，哈希始终是p的模。
AUDIENCE: Oh that's true, OK.
听众：哦，是的，好的。
PROFESSOR: So as long as p is decent,
教授：只要p像样，
it's not going to get too big.
它不会变得太大。
AUDIENCE: All right.
听众：好的。
What if old and new [INAUDIBLE]--
如果新旧[听不清]
PROFESSOR: So old and new--
教授：如此古老又崭新-
AUDIENCE: P is a big number .
听众：P是一个大数字。
314159269 is possibly bigger than your word size, right?
314159269可能大于您的单词大小，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Definitely.
教授：当然可以。
So that's why we're getting rid of it.
这就是为什么我们要摆脱它。
AUDIENCE: That is true. [INAUDIBLE]
听众：是的。 [听不清]
PROFESSOR: So this is k digits in base b.
教授：所以这是基数b的k位数字。
Too much.
太多了。
Not going to deal with it.
不打算处理它。
Hash is one digit in base p, because we're doing it mod p.
哈希是基数p中的一位数字，因为我们在mod p中进行操作。
Old and new are one digit base b.
新旧都是一位数字基数b。
So hopefully small numbers.
希望人数少。
OK, I haven't seen a constructor in CLRS,
好的，我没有在CLRS中看到构造函数，
so I'm going to say that when you write pseudocode,
所以我要说的是，当您编写伪代码时，
the method name for a constructor
构造函数的方法名称
is in it because we've seen this before.
之所以在其中是因为我们之前已经看过这个。
And let's say our constructor for a rolling cache
假设我们的滚动缓存的构造函数
starts with the base that we're going to use.
从我们将要使用的基础开始。
And it builds an empty rolling hash,
它建立了一个空的滚动哈希，
so first there's nothing in it.
首先，它什么都没有。
And then you append and you skip and you can get the hash.
然后追加并跳过，就可以得到哈希值。
AUDIENCE: What about p?
听众：p呢？
Shouldn't you also do p?
你不也应该做p吗？
PROFESSOR: Sure.
教授：当然可以。
Do that.
去做。
So let's say base and p are set, so somethings sets base and p.
假设设置了base和p，那么有些东西设置了base和p。
And we need to compute the initial values
我们需要计算初始值
for hash and magic.
哈希和魔术。
What's hash?
什么是哈希？
Zero.
零。
There's nothing in there, right?
那里什么都没有，对不对？
The number is 0.
数字是0。
What's magic?
魔术是什么？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
Well, I mean, you can calculate it, right?
好吧，我的意思是，您可以计算出来，对吧？
PROFESSOR: So magic is based to the size mod p.
教授：魔术是基于mod p的大小。
What size?
什么尺寸？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] 0.
观众：[听不清] 0。
Just one mod p.
仅一个mod p。
PROFESSOR: Yep.
教授：是的。
So when I start, I have an empty sliding window.
因此，当我开始时，我有一个空的滑动窗口。
Nothing in there, size is 0, base to the size
那里什么都没有，大小为0，以大小为基础
is 1, whatever the size is.
是1，无论大小是多少。
Very good.
很好。
Let's write append.
让我们写一个追加。
Hash is?
哈希是？
So here, we're doing both an append and the skip.
因此，在这里，我们同时执行附加操作和跳过操作。
We have to figure out which operation belongs
我们必须弄清楚哪个操作属于
to the append, which operations belong to the skip.
到追加，哪些操作属于跳过。
So someone help me out.
所以有人帮我。
AUDIENCE: We know subtraction would [INAUDIBLE]--
听众：我们知道减法会[听不清]-
AUDIENCE: Multiply mod base [INAUDIBLE].
听众：乘以mod base [听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So this is the append, right?
这是附加项，对不对？
And this is the skip.
这就是跳过。
So hash equals hash.
因此，哈希等于哈希。
Times base plus new mod p.
时基加上新的mod p。
Very good.
很好。
This is important.
这个很重要。
If you don't put this in, Python knows
如果不输入，Python就会知道
how to deal with big numbers.
如何处理大数字。
So it will take your code and it'll run it,
因此，它将使用您的代码并运行它，
and you'll get the correct output.
您将获得正确的输出。
But hash will keep growing and growing and growing
但是哈希将不断增长
because you're computing n instead of hash.
因为您要计算n而不是哈希。
And you'll wonder why the code is so slow.
您会想知道为什么代码这么慢。
So don't forget this.
所以不要忘记这一点。
What else do I need to update?
我还需要更新什么？
OK, I don't have a constant for that,
好吧，我没有一个常数
but I have a constant I for something else.
但是我有一个不变的自我。
Magic.
魔法。
So magic is base to the size mod p.
因此，魔术是大小mod p的基础。
So what happened to the window size?
那么窗口大小发生了什么？
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
Times base [INAUDIBLE].
时基[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: Excellent.
教授：非常好。
The window size grows by 1, therefore,
窗口大小增加1，因此，
I have to multiply this by base.
我必须将此乘以基数。
Magic times base mod p.
魔法时代基础MOD p。
AUDIENCE: Does p always have to be less then the base,
听众：p是否必须总是小于基数，
or can it be anything?
或者可以是什么？
PROFESSOR: It can be bigger than the base.
教授：它可以比基数大。
So if I want to not have a lot of false positives,
因此，如果我不想有很多误报，
then suppose my base is 256, because that's
然后假设我的底数是256，因为那是
an extra character.
一个额外的字符。
I was arguing earlier that the number of false positives
我之前说过，误报的数量
that I have is 1/P basically.
我拥有的基本上是1 / P。
So I want p to be as close to the word size as possible.
所以我希望p尽可能接近字长。
So p will be around 2 to the 4 billion.
因此p将在2到40亿之间。
So definitely bigger.
所以绝对更大。
It can work either way.
它可以以任何一种方式工作。
It's better if it's bigger for the algorithm
算法越大越好
that we're using there.
我们在那里使用。
All right, good question, thank you.
好的，好的问题，谢谢。
Skip.
跳跃。
Let's implement skip.
让我们实现跳过。
Hash is?
哈希是？
AUDIENCE: Hash minus old [INAUDIBLE] then comes magic
听众：哈希减去旧的[听不清]然后变魔术
[INAUDIBLE].
[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, can I write this in Python?
教授：好的，我可以用Python编写吗？
What happens if I write this?
如果我写这个怎么办？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] magic is, [INAUDIBLE] We
听众：[听不清]魔术是[听不清]我们
won't be able to find it.
将找不到它。
PROFESSOR: OK so-- sorry, not in Python.
教授：好的，对不起，不是Python。
So assume all these are instance variables done the right way,
因此，假设所有这些都是正确执行的实例变量，
but what happens if old times magic is bigger than hash?
但是，如果以前的魔术比哈希大，会发生什么？
I get a negative number.
我得到一个负数。
And in math, people assume that if you
在数学上，人们认为如果
do something like minus 3 modulo 23, you're going to get 20.
做类似负3模23的事情，您将得到20。
So modulo is always positive in modular arithmetic,
所以模在模算术中总是正的，
but in a programming language, if you do minus 3 modulo 20,
但是用一种编程语言，如果您做负3模20
I'm pretty sure you're going to get minus 3.
我很确定您会得到减3。
And things will go back.
事情会回到过去。
So we want to get to a positive number
所以我们想得到一个正数
here so that the arithmetic modulo
在这里这样算术模
p will work just like in math.
p会像在数学上一样工作。
So we want to add something to make this whole thing positive.
因此，我们想添加一些东西来使整个事情变得积极。
AUDIENCE: That's something times [INAUDIBLE].
听众：有时候[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: OK, so if we're working modulo p
教授：好的，所以如果我们以p为模
then we can add anything to our number, any multiple of p,
那么我们可以将任何东西加到p的任何倍数上
and the result modulo p doesn't change.
结果，模p不变。
For example, here to get from minus 3 to 20, I added 23.
例如，这里是从负3到20，我加了23。
Right?
对？
OK, so I want to add a correction
好，所以我想添加一个更正
factor of p times something.
p倍的东西。
So what should that be?
那应该是什么？
I want to make sure that this whole thing is positive.
我想确保整个事情都是积极的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: So let's see.
教授：那么，让我们看看。
How big are these guys, by the way?
这些家伙有多大？
Magic is something mod p, right?
魔术是mod p的东西，对不对？
So it's definitely smaller or equal to p.
因此，它肯定小于或等于p。
How about old?
老了吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So smaller or equal than?
小于或等于？
AUDIENCE: Base.
听众：基础。
PROFESSOR: Base.
教授：基地。
Very good.
很好。
So this whole thing is definitely
所以这件事绝对是
going to be smaller than [INAUDIBLE].
会比[音频不清晰]小。
So this is definitely going to be smaller than base time p,
因此，这肯定会小于基准时间p，
right?
对？
So let's put that in here.
因此，我们将其放在这里。
You can get fancy and say hey, this is smaller than p,
您可以幻想说，这比p小，
and this is old, so you can put old here instead, same thing.
这是旧的，所以您可以在同一位置放旧。
OK so we have hash.
好，所以我们有哈希。
Now what do we do to magic?
现在我们该怎么做魔术？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] divide it by the base and mod p.
听众：[听不清]将其除以基数和mod p。
It seems base [? and p ?] don't share factors.
看来基础[？和p？]不共享因素。
You're allowed to do that?
你被允许这样做吗？
PROFESSOR: OK, so skip part two.
教授：好的，所以跳过第二部分。
Magic equals-- So what if my magic is something like 5
魔法等于-如果我的魔法是5
and my base is 100?
我的底数是100？
How is this going to work?
这如何运作？
This is where we use fancy math.
这是我们使用奇特数学的地方。
And I call it fancy math because I
我称它为奇特数学，因为我
didn't learn it in high school.
在高中没学过
So I'm assuming at least some of you do not know how this works.
因此，我假设至少有些人不知道这是如何工作的。
So if we're working modulo p, you
因此，如果我们以p为模，则您
can think 23 if you prefer concrete numbers instead.
如果您更喜欢具体数字，可以考虑23。
For any number between 1 and p minus 1,
对于1到p减去1之间的任何数字
there's something called the multiplicative inverse,
有一种叫做乘法逆的东西
a to the minus 1, that also happens
a到负1，也会发生
to be an integer between 1 and p minus 1.
为1到p减1之间的整数。
And if you multiply, say, a times b, that's another number.
如果乘以b，则这是另一个数字。
And then you multiply this by a minus 1,
然后将其乘以减1，
you're going to get to b modulo p.
您将获得b模p。
So a minus 1 cancels a in a multiplication.
因此，负1会取消乘法。
Now let's see if you guys are paying attention.
现在让我们看看你们是否在关注。
What's a times a to the minus 1 modulo p?
负1模p乘a的倍数是多少？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Sweet.
甜。
So suppose I want to find the multiplicative inverse of 6.
因此，假设我想找到6的乘法逆。
What is it?
它是什么？
AUDIENCE: Is that the mod 23?
听众：是mod 23吗？
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Can someone think of what it should be?
有人能想到它应该是什么吗？
AUDIENCE: 4.
听众：4。
PROFESSOR: 4, wow, fast.
教授：4，哇，快。
So 6 times 4 equals 24, which is 1 modulo 23.
因此6乘以4等于24，即1为模23。
Now let's see if this magic really works, this math magic.
现在，让我们看看这种魔术是否真的有效，这种数学魔术。
So 6 times 7 equals?
那么6乘以7等于？
AUDIENCE: 42.
听众：42。
PROFESSOR: Which is what mod 23?
教授：哪个是mod 23？
Computer guys.
电脑家伙。
AUDIENCE: Negative 4, so 5.
观众：负面4，所以5。
Ah, just kidding.
啊，开玩笑。
Yeah.
是的
PROFESSOR: OK now let's multiply 19 by 4.
教授：好的，现在我们将19乘以4。
What is this?
这是什么？
AUDIENCE: 76.
观众：76。
PROFESSOR: All right, 76 modulo 23?
教授：好的，以23为模数吗？
AUDIENCE: 7 maybe.
听众：也许7。
PROFESSOR: Are you kidding?
教授：你在开玩笑吗？
Did you compute it, or did you use--
您是计算出来的，还是使用了-
AUDIENCE: 69 [INAUDIBLE]
观众：69 [听不清]
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
Started with 7, ended with 7.
以7开头，以7结束。
So this works.
所以这可行。
So as long we're working modulo a prime number,
因此，只要我们以质数为模，
we can always compute multiplicative inverses.
我们总是可以计算乘法逆。
And Python has a function for that,
Python为此提供了一个功能，
so I'll let you Google its standard library
所以我会让你Google的标准库
to find out what it is.
找出它是什么。
But it can be done, that's what matters
但是可以做到的，那才是最重要的
as far as we're concerned.
就我们而言。
So we're going to say that magic is magic times base minus 1 mod
所以我们要说魔法是魔法乘以基础减去1 mod
p, which is the multiplicative inverse everything mod p.
p，它是所有乘数逆模p。
Now suppose this base minus 1 modulo p,
现在假设这个基数减去1模p
this multiplicative inverse algorithm is really slow.
这种乘法逆算法确实很慢。
What do we do to stay order 1?
我们如何保持订单1？
Pre compute it.
预先计算。
Base is not going to change.
基础不会改变。
Very good.
很好。
So the inverse of base, I base, is base minus 1 mod p.
因此，底数的倒数I base为底数减去1 mod p。
So here I replace this with I base.
所以在这里我用我的基地代替。
OK so skip part one is there, skip part two is here.
确定，所以跳过第一部分，这里跳过第二部分。
Does this make sense so far?
到目前为止，这有意义吗？
I see some confusion.
我有些困惑。
AUDIENCE: A lot.
听众：很多。
PROFESSOR: A lot to take in at once?
教授：一次可以吸收很多东西吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So remember this concept.
所以请记住这个概念。
So this is where we started from.
这就是我们的起点。
Then we computed n, then after n, we
然后我们计算n，然后在n之后，我们
worked modulo p to gets to hashes.
用模p运算得到哈希值。
So by working module p, we're able to get rid
所以通过工作模块p，我们可以摆脱
of all the big numbers and we only
在所有大数字中，我们只
have small numbers in our rolling hash.
在滚动哈希中有少量数字。
And there's that curveball there, there
那里有曲线球
is that inverse, multiplicative inverse,
是逆，乘法逆，
but Python computes it for you, so
但Python会为您进行计算，因此
as long as it's in the initializer,
只要在初始化程序中
here you don't need to worry about it,
在这里，您不必担心，
because it's not part of the rolling hash operations.
因为它不是滚动哈希操作的一部分。
By the way, what's the cost of the rolling hash operations?
顺便说一下，滚动哈希运算的成本是多少？
What's the cost of new?
新产品的成本是多少？
Sorry, what's the cost of append?
抱歉，追加费用是多少？
Not thinking here.
不在这里思考。
Constant.
不变。
All these are small numbers, so the arithmetic
这些都是小数字，所以算术
is constant, right?
是恒定的，对吗？
What's the cost of skip?
跳过的费用是多少？
Skip part 1 here, skip part two there.
在此处跳过第1部分，在此处跳过第2部分。
What's the cost of skip?
跳过的费用是多少？
Constant. .
不变。 。
All the numbers are small.
所有数字都很小。
We went through a lot of effort to get that,
我们为此付出了很多努力，
so skip is order 1.
所以跳过是订单1。
We're missing hash.
我们缺少哈希。
How would we implement the hash operation?
我们将如何实现哈希运算？
A hash query.
哈希查询。
It's easy.
这很容易。
Sorry?
抱歉？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] lookup [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]查找[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: So a rolling hash has append, skip, and hash.
教授：因此，滚动哈希具有附加，跳过和哈希。
I want to implement that hash function.
我想实现该哈希函数。
Hash.
哈希。
We're computing hash all the time.
我们一直在计算哈希。
Return.
返回。
Sorry, I didn't understand what you meant by lookup.
抱歉，我不明白您的查询含义。
AUDIENCE: It's one of our states.
听众：这是我们的州之一。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
Exactly.
究竟。
So the hash function returns hash, right?
所以hash函数返回hash，对不对？
What's the cost of that?
费用是多少？
Constant.
不变。
So append is constant time, yes?
因此，append是固定时间的，是吗？
Skip is constant time.
跳过是固定时间。
Hash is constant time.
哈希是固定时间。
We're done.
大功告成
This works.
这可行。
Any questions on rolling hashes before you
在滚动哈希之前有任何疑问
have to implement one of your own?
必须实施自己的一种？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] wouldn't it
听众：[听不清]
be easier to use a shift function?
更容易使用移位功能？
Then you don't have to think about plus and minus.
然后，您不必考虑加号和减号。
PROFESSOR: A shift function.
教授：移位功能。
AUDIENCE: Well I mean like, you can shift bit-wise, right?
听众：我的意思是，你可以按位转移，对吗？
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
AUDIENCE: So you can just use shift
听众：所以你可以使用shift
instead of thinking about where to add this,
而不是考虑将其添加到何处，
where to subtract this.
在哪里减去这个。
PROFESSOR: Well so I do bit operations
教授：好吧，我来做位手术
if I'm willing to work with these big numbers.
如果我愿意处理这些大数字。
AUDIENCE: But then you have to compute
听众：但是那你得计算一下
the mod of some big number, right?
一些大数的mod，对吗？
Like just like that.
就像那样。
For this one, you don't have to, because you
对于这个，您不必这样做，因为您
have the original hash [INAUDIBLE].
具有原始哈希值[INAUDIBLE]。
AUDIENCE: Oh, you mean the big number
听众：哦，你的意思是很大
being the actual word you're looking at?
是您正在查看的实际单词？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
PROFESSOR: So doing shift is equivalent to maintaining
教授：所以换班等于维持
a list and pushing and popping things into the list.
列表，然后将内容推送到列表中。
And then you have to do a hash, it's
然后你必须做一个哈希，
equivalent to looking over the entire list
相当于查看整个列表
and computing the hash function.
并计算哈希函数。
Because you'd have a big number and you have to take
因为你人数很多，你必须带走
it modulo 23.
它的模数为23
And that's order of the size of the big number.
这就是大数字的顺序。
But we're not allowed to do that.
但是我们不允许这样做。
Hash has to be constant time, otherwise this thing is slow.
哈希必须是固定的时间，否则这个东西很慢。
AUDIENCE: Why do we compute magic numbers then?
听众：为什么我们要计算魔术数呢？
PROFESSOR: Why do we compute magic?
教授：为什么我们要计算魔术？
We compute magic because somewhere here, we
我们计算魔术是因为在这里
had this base to the size mod p and this could get big.
这个基数的大小为mod p，这可能会变大。
So I can't afford to keep it around and do math
所以我负担不起去做数学
with it all the time.
一直都有。
So I can't compute base to the size
所以我无法计算出基本尺寸
every time I want to do append.
每次我想附加。
AUDIENCE: Would it be worth it if you're computing 100
观众：如果您计算100，那值得吗
different values for matching and [INAUDIBLE],
匹配和[音频不清晰]的值不同，
so all you'd have to do is, when reassigning magic,
所以您要做的就是在重新分配魔术时，
just look up--
抬头-
PROFESSOR: So if you do that, then you
教授：所以，如果您这样做，那么您
have to compute values for all the sizes, right?
必须计算所有尺寸的值，对不对？
For all the window sizes.
对于所有窗口大小。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
So if we assume that window sizes will be less than 100,
因此，如果我们假设窗口大小小于100，
it doesn't take very long.
不需要很长时间。
PROFESSOR: Well what if the window size is 1 million?
教授：那么如果窗口大小为100万怎么办？
What if I'm looking for a 1 million
如果我要寻找一百万
character in a 1 gigabyte string?
1 GB字符串中的字符？
AUDIENCE: But wouldn't after all, wouldn't the size just
听众：但是毕竟不会，大小不会
be around the string, like plus or minus the size of the base?
是围绕字符串，如正负号的大小？
So--
所以 -
AUDIENCE: Only if [INAUDIBLE]
听众：仅当[听不清]
So why would the size change again?
那么，为什么尺寸会再次改变？
Why wouldn't it just be-- I mean,
为什么不是-我的意思是，
if you're looking at one character.
如果您正在看一个字符。
PROFESSOR: So if I have a sliding window like this,
教授：所以，如果我有一个这样的滑动窗口，
then it doesn't change.
那么它不会改变。
But if I want to implement a rolling hash,
但是如果我想实现滚动哈希，
that's a bit more general and that supports append and skip.
这有点通用，并且支持追加和跳过。
Whenever I append, the size increases.
每当我追加时，大小都会增加。
Whenever I skip, the size decreases.
每当我跳过时，大小都会减小。
AUDIENCE: Oh, you're not doing those at every time step.
听众：哦，您不是在每个步骤中都这样做。
You're doing them as needed.
您正在根据需要进行操作。
PROFESSOR: So I'm trying to implement
教授：所以我正在尝试实施
that, that can do them in any sequence.
那可以按任何顺序完成
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
I thought we were just doing sliding window.
我以为我们只是在做滑动窗。
PROFESSOR: So if we're just doing sliding window, you can--
教授：所以，如果我们只是做滑动窗，您可以-
AUDIENCE: This is really more caterpillar hash instead
观众：这实际上是更多的毛毛虫哈希
of rolling hash, like it's more general.
滚动哈希，就像它更通用一样。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
It's a bit more general.
比较一般。
So let's look at rolling hash for the window.
因此，让我们来看一下窗口的滚动哈希。
And what you're saying is, hey, the window size
你的意思是，窗口大小
is constant, so--
是恒定的，所以-
AUDIENCE: Why do we repeat magic [INAUDIBLE]?
听众：我们为什么要重复魔术[听不清]？
PROFESSOR: Yeah, if the window size is constant,
教授：是的，如果窗口大小不变，
then we wouldn't re compute it.
那么我们就不会重新计算它。
It wouldn't change.
它不会改变。
But with this thing, it's not.
但事实并非如此。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: But I guess it doesn't really matter,
听众：但是我想这并不重要，
but even if you call these in the same order,
但是即使您以相同的顺序调用它们，
then isn't that wasting a lot of computing cycles
那不是浪费很多计算周期
because just shrinking and then growing every single operation?
因为只是缩小然后增加每个操作？
PROFESSOR: Oh, well it turns out that a lot of computing cycles
教授：哦，事实证明，很多计算周期
is still order one, right?
还是一号吧？
Everything is order one.
一切都是第一。
So as algorithms people, we don't care.
因此，作为算法人员，我们不在乎。
If you're doing it in a system and you actually
如果您是在系统中进行操作，而实际上
care about that, then OK.
关心那个，然后确定。
But you're still going to have to compute
但是您仍然需要计算
the initial value at some point.
某个时候的初始值。
AUDIENCE: But if you know window's staying the same,
听众：但是，如果您知道窗户保持不变，
you don't need to that computation every time?
您不需要每次都进行该计算吗？
PROFESSOR: If you-- sorry?
教授：对不起？
AUDIENCE: If you know you're actually
听众：如果您知道自己实际上是
just doing a window rolling hash--
只是做一个窗口滚动哈希-
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So then you would initialize magic here
因此，您将在此处初始化魔术
to be whatever you want it to be, right?
成为你想要的东西吧？
But then when you add the first few characters to the window,
但是，当您将前几个字符添加到窗口时，
you have to figure out how to add them.
您必须弄清楚如何添加它们。
So the code gets more messy.
因此，代码变得更加混乱。
It turns out that this is actually
原来，这实际上是
simpler than doing it that way.
比那样做更简单。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] magic I guess
听众：我猜是[听不清]魔术
I'm just confused because it seems like we're still working
我很困惑，因为好像我们还在工作
with the large numbers every time [INAUDIBLE].
每次[听不清]时都有大量数字。
PROFESSOR: Oh.
教授：哦。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
Mod p, mod p.
Mod p，mod p。
AUDIENCE: That's not-- so even though you're still multiplying
听众：并非如此-即使您仍在繁殖
magic times base, it doesn't matter.
魔术时代的基础，没关系。
PROFESSOR: After I'm going that, I'm reducing it modulo p.
教授：之后，我将其以p为模降低。
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: And then because we're only
听众：然后因为我们只是
working with the smaller values.
使用较小的值。
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So everything here stays between 0 and base or 0 and p.
因此，这里的所有内容都保持在0到base或0到p之间。
Actually hash is between 0 and p and magic is between 0 and p.
实际上，哈希值介于0和p之间，而魔术值介于0和p之间。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: How big does p usually get?
听众：p通常能变多大？
PROFESSOR: How big does p usually get.
教授：p通常会变大。
So And let me get back to this.
所以，让我回到这一点。
So I was arguing that the number of false positives
所以我在争论误报的数量
here is one over O, right?
这是O之上的一个，对吧？
is the number of values that the hash function can output.
是哈希函数可以输出的值的数量。
How many hash functions can we output using a rolling hash?
我们可以使用滚动散列输出多少个散列函数？
AUDIENCE: P.
听众：P.
PROFESSOR: P. OK.
教授：好的。
So the number of false positives is
所以误报的数量是
1/P. So what do we want for p?
1 / P。那么我们想要p呢？
AUDIENCE: We want p to be the word size, because but if p's
观众：我们希望p为字长，因为如果p为
the word size, then--
字号，然后-
PROFESSOR: So p can't be the word size,
教授：所以p不能是字长，
because it has to be prime, right?
因为它必须是素数，对吗？
But we want it to be big, because as p becomes bigger,
但是我们希望它更大，因为随着p变大，
1/P becomes smaller.
1 / P变小。
So there are two constraints.
因此有两个约束。
We want p to be big so that we don't
我们希望p很大，这样我们就不会
have a lot of false positives.
有很多误报。
And we want p to be small so that operations
而且我们希望p较小，以便运算
don't take a lot of time.
不需要很多时间。
So in engineering, this is how things work.
因此，在工程中，这就是工作原理。
We call it a tradeoff because there
我们称其为权衡，因为那里
are forces pushing in opposite directions,
是朝相反方向推动的力量，
and it turns out that a reasonable answer to the trade
事实证明，对交易的合理回答
off is you make p fit in a word so that all those operations
你是说p使p合适，以便所有这些操作
are still implementable by one CPU instruction.
仍然可以由一条CPU指令实现。
You can't have it be the word size.
您不能拥有字号。
So if we're working on a 32-bit computer,
因此，如果我们在32位计算机上工作，
I can't have this be 2 to the 32.
我不能让这个数字等于32。
But I can have a prime number that's just a little bit
但是我可以有一个质数
smaller than 2 to the 32.
小于2到32。
AUDIENCE: Wait, why can't it be the word size?
听众：等等，为什么不能是字号？
Or why can't it be 2 to the 32?
或者为什么它不能是32的2？
PROFESSOR: So if p would be this instead of a prime,
教授：所以如果p是这个而不是质数，
then I can't do this.
那我就做不到
AUDIENCE: Oh, right right right, yeah I knew that.
听众：哦，对，对，对，我知道。
PROFESSOR: There are a lot of moving parts here
教授：这里有很多活动部件
and they're all interconnected.
他们都是相互联系的。
AUDIENCE: You could do that for any prime number, right?
听众：你可以用任何素数来做，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So this works for prime numbers, but it
所以这适用于素数，但是
doesn't work for non prime numbers.
对非素数不起作用。
AUDIENCE: You could find the multiplicative inverse
听众：您可以找到乘法逆
for any prime number in base 32.
以32为底的任何质数
Is that true?
真的吗？
I mean any odd number is what I'm trying to say.
我的意思是我要说的是奇数。
No, that's not true.
不，那不是真的。
PROFESSOR: I refuse to answer hard math questions.
教授：我拒绝回答数学难题。
AUDIENCE: They need to be relatively prime.
听众：他们需要相对重要。
They need to share no factors.
他们无需分享任何因素。
PROFESSOR: Yes, it might be true.
教授：是的，可能是事实。
AUDIENCE: So an odd will not share a factor with 2
观众：所以奇数不会与2共享一个因数
to the 32?
到32？
PROFESSOR: You're forcing me to remember hard math.
教授：您在逼我记住硬数学。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, I totally just thought about this
听众：是的，我完全想到了
as [INAUDIBLE] number.
作为[音频不清晰]号。
PROFESSOR: So, no, it turns out that there's
教授：所以，不，事实证明
no-- if you're working modulo and non prime base, then
否-如果您使用的是模数和非素数基数，则
there's no multiplicity inverses.
没有多重逆。
So some numbers have no multiplicative inverses,
所以有些数字没有乘法逆，
and other numbers have more than one multiplicative inverse.
其他数字有一个以上的乘法逆。
And then the whole thing doesn't work.
然后整个事情就不起作用了。
So let me see if I can make this work
所以让我看看我是否可以做这项工作
without having an example by hand.
没有手举一个例子。
Let's say we're working mod 8, right?
假设我们正在使用mod 8，对吗？
Mod 8.
Mod 8。
So 2 to the minus 1 mod 8 is not going to exist, right?
所以2减1 mod 8将不存在，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Right, but 3 will.
听众：是的，但3个会。
PROFESSOR: 3.
教授：3。
Let's see what do we use?
让我们看看我们用什么？
3 times 3 is 9, right?
3乘3等于9，对不对？
So this is 1.
所以这是1。
How about 3 times 5?
3乘5怎么样？
15 mod 8 is 7.
15 mod 8是7。
So 3 and 5, and then--
所以3和5，然后-
AUDIENCE: 11.
听众：11。
PROFESSOR: OK.
教授：好的。
So 3 times 7 would be 21, 5.
所以7的3乘以21，5。
OK so 3 and-- 3 is the multiplicative inverse
好吧3和-3是乘法逆
of itself, and 5 and 7 are-- yeah.
本身，而5和7是-是的。
I have to build a more complicated example,
我必须建立一个更复杂的例子
but this breaks down in some cases.
但这在某些情况下会失败。
I'll have to get back to you.
我得回覆你。
I will look at my notes for modular arithmetic
我将看一下有关模块化算术的笔记
and I'll get back to you guys over email
我会通过电子邮件回复你们
for why and how that breaks.
为什么会这样以及如何打破。
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: Sorry, can you tell me again
听众：对不起，你能再告诉我吗
why we did the part 2 in skip?
为什么我们跳过了第2部分？
Like why did we do that?
就像我们为什么要这样做？
I'm not really sure [INAUDIBLE].
我不确定[音频不清晰]。
PROFESSOR: So we started with magic 1
教授：所以我们从魔术1开始
and then we-- in order for this to work,
然后我们-为了使它起作用，
we agree that magic will be base to the size modulo p
我们同意魔术将成为模数p的基础
all the time.
每时每刻。
So this has to be [INAUDIBLE] invariant for my rolling hash.
因此，对于我的滚动哈希，这必须是[音频不可变]。
When I do an append, the size increases by 1.
当我执行追加操作时，大小增加1。
And then I multiply by base to modulo p.
然后我乘以基数以求模p。
When I do a skip, the size decreases by 1.
当我跳过时，大小减小1。
So I have to change magic, because magic is always
所以我必须改变魔术，因为魔术总是
base times size, so I have to update it.
基本时间大小，因此我必须对其进行更新。
So this is why this happened.
这就是为什么发生这种情况。
Because initially, I wanted to update
因为最初我想更新
by dividing it by base, right?
将其除以基数，对吗？
Magic divided by base.
魔术除以基础。
But if magic is 5 and base is 100,
但是如果魔术是5，底数是100，
we're not going to get an integer.
我们不会得到一个整数。
And we want to stay within integers,
我们希望保持在整数范围内，
so that's when I pulled out fancy math and-- OK.
所以那时候我拿出了花哨的数学，而且-好。
OK.
好。
So how are we doing with rolling hashes?
那么，如何处理哈希值呢？
Good?
好？
AUDIENCE: All this math will be in the notes, right?
听众：所有这些数学都在笔记中，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Everything.
教授：一切。
Oh, yeah, everything else will be in the notes.
哦，是的，其他所有内容都将在笔记中。
Before we close out, I want to show you one cute thing.
在结束之前，我想向您展示一件可爱的东西。
Who remembers amortized analysis?
谁还记得摊销分析？
I know there's one person that said they understood.
我知道有人说他们了解。
All
所有
PROFESSOR: The growing, shrinking thing
教授：不断缩小的东西
is what we did in lecture.
这是我们在讲座中所做的。
I want to show something else.
我想展示些别的东西。
I want to show you a binary tree.
我想给你看一棵二叉树。
A binary search tree, because you've seen this on the PSAT
二进制搜索树，因为您已经在PSAT上看到了
and you already hate it.
你已经讨厌它了
AUDIENCE: Why'd they call it amortization?
听众：他们为什么称其为摊销？
Because I looked it up online, it means to kill,
因为我在网上查了一下，所以意味着要杀人，
and so I'm like, why not say like, attrition or something
所以我想，为什么不说减员之类的
else that's a little bit less--
否则要少一些
PROFESSOR: Amortization is also used in accounting to mean
教授：摊销在会计中也用来表示
you're--
你是 -
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插入语音]
PROFESSOR: Let's use the growing hash example,
教授：让我们使用不断增长的哈希示例，
because that's good for why this is the case.
因为那对为什么会这样是有好处的。
So when you're growing your table, you're inserting.
因此，当您扩大桌子时，就在插入。
If you still have space, that's order one.
如果您还有空间，那是第一个。
If not, you have to grow your table to insert.
如果不是，则必须扩大表才能插入。
And that is more expensive.
而且那更昂贵。
That's order n where n is how many elements you had before.
那是n阶，其中n是您之前有多少个元素。
So if you graph this costs, if you start off
因此，如果您以图形方式表示此成本，
with a table of size one, you can insert the first element
表格大小为1时，您可以插入第一个元素
for a cost of one.
只需一个。
For the second element, you have to resize the table,
对于第二个元素，您必须调整表的大小，
so it's a cost of two.
所以要花两个钱
Now when you're trying to insert the third element,
现在，当您尝试插入第三个元素时，
you have to resize the table again to a size of 4.
您必须再次将表格的大小调整为4。
But when you insert the fourth element, it's free.
但是，当您插入第四个元素时，它是免费的。
Well, cost of one.
好吧，一本钱。
When you insert the fifth element,
当您插入第五个元素时，
you have to resize a table to the size of eight, right?
您必须将一张桌子的大小调整为八个，对不对？
So The table size is one, two, four, four, and now it's eight.
所以表的大小是1、2、4、4，现在是8。
But because they resized this to eight,
但是由于他们将尺寸调整为八个，
the next three assertions are going to be order one.
接下来的三个断言将成为第一。
And then the one after that is going to make the table be 16.
然后，后面的一个将使该表为16。
So I can do seven insertions for free
所以我可以免费做七个插入
and then I'm going to have to pay
然后我要付钱
a lot more for the next one.
下一个要多得多。
Someone said dampening.
有人说阻尼。
I like dampening because the idea behind amortization
我喜欢减价，因为摊销背后的想法
is that you can take-- you have these big costs
是你可以承担的-你有这么大的代价
and they don't occur very often.
而且它们不经常发生。
So you can think of it as taking these big costs
因此，您可以将其视为承担这些巨大的成本
and chopping them up.
切碎
For example, I'm going to chop this up into four
例如，我将把它分成四个部分
and I'm going to take this piece and put it here.
我要把这块放到这里。
This piece and put it here.
这一块，放在这里。
And then I'm going to chop this guy into two,
然后我要把这个人切成两半，
and then take this piece and put it here.
然后把这块放到这里
And the beginning's a little bit weird,
开始有点奇怪
let's not worry about that but this guy,
让我们不用担心，但是这个人，
if I chop this guy up into eight, it's going to happen,
如果我把这个人切成八块，那将会发生，
is it?
是吗？
Well we can put-- so this guy grows exponentially, right?
好吧，我们可以这样说-这个家伙成倍增长，对吧？
Every time it's multiplied by 2.
每次乘以2。
But the gap size here also is multiplied by 2.
但是这里的间隙大小也要乘以2。
So when I chop this up and I re distribute the pieces,
因此，当我将其切碎并重新分配时，
it turns out that the pieces are the same size.
事实证明，碎片是相同的大小。
So if I apply a dampening function that does this,
因此，如果我应用阻尼功能来做到这一点，
then the costs are going to look-- they're not
那么成本会看起来-他们不是
going to be on one, they there are
将会合而为一，他们在那里
going to be three or something.
将会是三岁左右。
And they look like this.
他们看起来像这样。
Now, my CPU time is going to look like this, right?
现在，我的CPU时间看起来像这样，对吧？
That's not going to change, because that's
那不会改变，因为那是
what's really happening.
到底发生了什么
But what I can argue for is that if I
但是我可以主张的是，如果我
look for a bunch of operations, say if I look at the first 16
寻找一堆操作，如果我看一下前16个
insertions, the cost of those is the sum of these guys.
插入，这些的成本是这些家伙的总和。
So it's not been squared, which is
所以它不是平方的，这是
what you would get if you look at the worst cases here,
如果看这里最坏的情况，你会得到什么，
but it's order n.
但这是命令n
So this is what's being dampened,
所以这就是被抑制的东西，
the amount of time an operation takes.
一项操作花费的时间。
Does this make some sense?
这有意义吗？
All right, I want to show you a cute example for amortization.
好吧，我想向您展示一个可爱的摊销示例。
And I'll try to make it quick.
而且我会尽力使其快速。
So how do you list the keys in a binary search tree in order?
那么，如何在二进制搜索树中按顺序列出关键字？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: In order traversal, right?
教授：为了遍历，对不对？
OK, there's another way of doing it
好，还有另一种方法
that makes perfect intuitive sense.
这具有完美的直观意义。
Get the minimum key, right?
得到最小的钥匙吧？
And then output the minimum key, then
然后输出最小键，然后
while you can get the next largest, which
而您可以获得下一个最大的
is the successor-- so while this is not,
是继任者-所以虽然不是，
now output that key, right?
现在输出该密钥，对吗？
If you do the thing within order traversal,
如果您在订单遍历范围内进行操作，
you get order end running time.
您将获得订单结束运行时间。
What's the running time for this?
这是什么时间？
AUDIENCE: For n.
听众：对于n。
You're going through all the keys, too.
您也正在浏览所有键。
PROFESSOR: Yeah, but next largest--
教授：是的，但是第二大
what's the running time for next largest?
下一个最大的运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: Log n.
听众：登录n。
PROFESSOR: So this guy's log in, right?
教授：那么这个人的登录对吗？
So I have n keys, so this whole thing is O of n logn.
所以我有n个键，所以整个事情是n logn的O。
So it's definitely not bigger than n logn.
因此，它绝对不大于n logn。
But now, let's look at what happens using the tree.
但是现在，让我们看看使用树会发生什么。
When I call min, I go down on each edge.
当我打电话给min时，我在每条边上走下去。
And then I call successor and it outputs this guy.
然后我称呼后继者，它输出了这个家伙。
Then I call successor and it goes here.
然后我称呼后继者，它就在这里。
Than I call successor and it goes up here and here
比我称呼继任者更是如此
and outputs this guy.
并输出这个家伙。
Successor goes here.
继任者去这里。
Successor goes all the way down here, successor goes up here,
继任者一直走到这里，继任者往上走，
successor goes here, and then successor
继任者去这里，然后继任者
goes all the way up to the roots and gives up.
一直扎根，放弃。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
PROFESSOR: So how many times do I traverse each edge?
教授：那么我要遍历每个边缘多少次？
Exactly twice, right?
正好两次，对不对？
How many edges in the tree?
树上有多少条边？
If I have n nodes, how many lines do I use to connect them?
如果我有n个节点，我要用几条线连接它们？
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
So 1 node, zero lines.
所以1个节点，零行。
2 nodes, one line.
2个节点，一行。
Three nodes, two lines.
三个节点，两行。
So n nodes, n minus one.
所以n个节点，n减1。
N asymptotically, good.
渐近地，N好。
Good answer.
好答案。
Order, n, edges.
顺序n个边。
Right, each edge gets traversed exactly twice.
正确，每个边缘正好遍历两次。
So amortized cost for n next largest operations is order n.
因此，n个下一个最大操作的摊销成本为订单n。
So you can do this instead.
因此，您可以改为执行此操作。
This code makes a lot more sense than in order traversal.
该代码比遍历顺序更有意义。
OK, and the last part is remember that list
好，最后一部分就是那个清单
query that was on the PSAT?
在PSAT上查询？
Turns out you can do a find for the lowest element
原来你可以找到最低的元素
and then call successor until you see the highest
然后呼叫后继，直到看到最高的
element for the same argument.
相同参数的元素。
Well, I couldn't tell you this for the PSAT
好吧，我无法告诉您有关PSAT的信息
because we hadn't learned amortized analysis,
因为我们还没有学会摊销分析，
so you wouldn't be able to prove that your code is fast.
因此您将无法证明自己的代码是快速的。
But now if you get the intuition,
但是现在如果你有了直觉，
you can write it that way.
你可以这样写。
And your code will still be fast.
而且您的代码仍然会很快。
Same running time.
相同的运行时间。
So the intuition for that is a bit more complicated.
所以直觉有点复杂。
The proof is more complicated.
证明更为复杂。
But the intuition is that say this is l and this is h.
但是直觉是说这是l，这是h。
Then I'm going to go in this tree here.
然后我要去这棵树。
So the same edge magic is going to happen,
所以同样的边缘魔法将会发生，
except there will be logn edges that are unmatched here
除非这里有不匹配的登录边缘
and logn edges that aren't unmatched here.
和此处未匹配的登录边缘。
Because once I find the node that's next to h,
因为一旦找到h旁边的节点，
I'll stop, right?
我会停下来吧？
So some edges will not be matched.
因此某些边缘将不匹配。
So then I'll say that the total running time is logn plus a.
因此，我将说总运行时间为logn加a。
AUDIENCE: i being the number of elements you pull out, right?
听众：我是你要抽出的元素数量，对吗？
PROFESSOR: Yup.
教授：是的。
So this is amortized analysis.
因此，这是摊销分析。
The list is hard.
清单很难。
The traversal is easy.
遍历很容易。
Remember the traversal.
记住遍历。
That's easy to reason about, so that's good.
这很容易推理，所以很好。
OK.
好。
Any questions on amortized analysis?
对摊销分析有任何疑问吗？
So the idea is that you look at all the operations,
因此，想法是您查看所有操作，
you don't look at one operation at a time.
您不会一次查看一项操作。
And you're trying to see if I look at everything,
而且您正在尝试查看我是否查看了所有内容，
is it the case that I have some really fast operations
我真的有一些快速操作的情况吗
and the slow operations don't happen
而且慢的操作不会发生
too much, because if that's the case,
太多，因为如果是这样，
then I can make an argument for the average cost, which
那么我可以对平均成本进行论证
is better than the argument that says this is the worst
比说这是最坏的说法更好
case of an operation, I'm doing an operation,
手术的情况下，我正在做手术，
the total cost is n times the worst cost.
总成本是最差成本的n倍。
Make some sense?
有道理吗？
OK.
好。
Cool.
凉。
All right.
好吧。
Have fun at the next p set.
在下一个p集玩得开心。